Objective

I want to deliver a strong message by making real changes aimed at improving and making the place we live in better. A place that allows people to have an obstacle-free path that allows unlimited growth. Therefore, I will dedicate my passion and ambition for problem-solving, analytical skills, and diverse and highly competent software engineering expertise in multiple fields to achieve this goal. Whatever it takes.

Education

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals (KFUPM)

Bachelor of Science, Software Engineering

Georgia Institute of Technology (GaTech)

Exchange Program, Computer Science

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Sep 2016 → May 2021

Atlanta, GA, United States

Aug 2019 → Dec 2019

Experience

Saudi Federation for Cyber Security and Programming (SAFCSP) ~ 8 months

Software Engineer

Empower the Saudi workforce through diverse bootcamps

Led a class of 25 students as part of the Tuwaig 1000 initiative

Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Sep 2021 → Jan 2022

Mar 2019 → Aug 2020

Jan 2022 → Present

Axenda ~ 2 years Remote

Founder & CEO Mar 2020 → Present

Work with a team of 2-98 people on various products and lead/manage when necessary

Mohtwize ~ 2 months Riyadh, Saudi Arabia

Aug 2021 → Sep 2021 Software Engineer

Worked with the product team as a system architect and developer

Udacity ~ 1.5 years Remote + Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

iOS Session Lead Trained more than 100 students on iOS development

TechBench ~ 2 years Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Oct 2018 → Aug 2020 Member / Tech Lead

Introduced tech to people via workshops and hackathons

Sary ~ 5 months Remote + Dammam, Saudi Arabia

Product Intern / Business Analyst

Mar 2020 → Jul 2020 Analyzed business processes for optimization and automation

King Fahd University of Petroleum & Minerals (KFUPM) ~ 7 months Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Database Systems Grader Feb 2020 → May 2020

Intro to Computing Grader Jun 2019 → Aug 2019

Continue Experience

Tweetso ~ 9 months
iOS Developer

Developed two applications (Experto & Experto Partners)

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia Nov 2017 → Jul 2018

Shahla ~ 8 years Alahsa, Saudi Arabia

Family Business
Worked as a cleaner, salesperson, inventory clerk, HR, driver, manager, and IT

Sep 2008 → Aug 2016

Awards

First Place at Aramco's Wa'ed Hackathon Dec 2018

Top Three at SAP-KAUST Hackathon Feb 2019

Volunteering

KFUPM Voluntary Work Unit

Volunteer

Dhahran, Saudi Arabia Feb 2018, 2019, 2020

Every year in February, I participate in a huge voluntary event where hundreds of my university students gather to help society through various initiatives.

Microsoft Dhahran, Saudi Arabia
Trainer Dec 2017

Worked along with Microsoft engineers as a trainer to introduce Microsoft's micro-computer, the micro:bit, to children via workshops.

Code.org Dhahran, Saudi Arabia
Trainer Dec 2017

Member of a team of 12 students from my university who volunteered to introduce basic programming knowledge through the Code.org platform to 402 young students throughout several workshops.

References

Salah Adam, Database Systems Assistant Professor at KFUPM

adam@kfupm.edu.sa

Dania Abedaljawad, Learning Experience Design Manager at Udacity dania.abedaljawad@udacity.com

Hussain Ali, Product Manager at Mohtwize hussain@mohtwize.com